<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Fabio M. Lopes</title>
    <link>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Fabio M. Lopes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.fabiolopes.tk/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scrapper using Python</title>
      <link>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/blog/python-web-scrapper-fii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/blog/python-web-scrapper-fii/</guid>
      <description>So I needed to learn how to scrape a web page using Python.
 My teammate suggested that I could learn a few tricks in python by scraping FIIs, which is the brazilian equivalent to american REITs. I did some research and found some good examples using a module called pandas (https://realpython.com/python-csv/) , a tool designed for data analisys and manipulation and very popular among people working with data science. My goal was much less ambitious but i thought i might as well use what everyone else is using, since it would provide a good learning opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparsion of Sorting Algorithms using Python Decorators</title>
      <link>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/blog/python-sort-comparsion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/blog/python-sort-comparsion/</guid>
      <description>So I needed to learn how to use decorators in Python.
 I tried to come up with something within my current knowledge and since I was studying sorting algorithms, I decided to use decorators to measure how long each algorithm would take to complete and compare them. I know that it is kind of obvious which one is better in the proposed scenario for anyone with a Bachelor in Computer Science or any experienced developer, but the purpose here was to learn and develop my python skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obtaining a list of Ceph features from the hexadecimal value</title>
      <link>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/blog/ceph-features-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fabiolopes.tk/blog/ceph-features-2/</guid>
      <description>After some digging i found the list of possible features, its respective kernel version requirement and/or when it became available.
 This can be found in src/include/ceph_features.h, and I got it by cloning the ceph repo at git://github.com/ceph/ceph .
That information might be useful when you are trying to determine if your clients might need a kernel upgrade and what kind of RBD or cephfs features you can enable on your server side without breaking compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>