<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on Fabio M. Lopes</title>
    <link>https://fabiolopes.page/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on Fabio M. Lopes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>fabioctba01@gmail.com (Fabio M. Lopes)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>fabioctba01@gmail.com (Fabio M. Lopes)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fabiolopes.page/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Local EKS Cluster on AWS Outposts</title>
      <link>https://fabiolopes.page/post/eks_outpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>fabioctba01@gmail.com (Fabio M. Lopes)</author>
      <guid>https://fabiolopes.page/post/eks_outpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terraform code provisions an EKS cluster on an AWS Outpost, with the control plane running locally on the Outpost. This differs significantly from deploying an EKS cluster in a standard AWS region, primarily in how worker nodes are managed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Amazon EKS update history demonstrates the platform&amp;rsquo;s continuous evolution, focusing on enhanced security, scalability, and integration with other AWS services. Since its initial release in June 2018, there&amp;rsquo;s been a significant increase in available features and functionalities, including support for newer Kubernetes versions, expansion to new AWS regions, and the introduction of new deployment options like Fargate and local clusters on AWS Outposts, which is the focus of this work. The introduction of features like managed node groups significantly simplified infrastructure management, automating tasks such as provisioning and lifecycle management of nodes. The availability of EKS-optimized AMIs, including options with GPU support and the Bottlerocket operating system, offers greater flexibility and performance for diverse workloads. Furthermore, integration with services like Amazon EBS, EFS, and FSx for Lustre, via CSI drivers, expanded storage options for the clusters. However, for a local Amazon EKS cluster on AWS Outposts, these resources are significantly more limited; managed node groups are unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
